-==http://www.1000fr.com==-
謦灵风软影视论坛荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-=风软FRM字幕组=-
翻译:HEBE 悭吝鬼
校对:悭吝鬼
我从没读过这样的剧本...
但是其中主要人物之间的关系...
得到了观众的认可
这点我很认可
What do you
think of her, Han?
I'm trying not to, kid.
Good.
剧本包罗万象
既有幽默 也不失真诚
Still, she's got a lot of spirit.
里面有海盗 有巫师
有农场男孩还有公主
And we had bickering robots,
and I thought, ''What's not to like?''
这种通俗的叙述方式让你可以...
进入人物的世界并享受这故事
星球大战的人物
它变成了一种文化现象
它的主题 语句...
May the Force be with you.
和人物在全球数百万人心中...
刻下了烙印
尽管星球大战的宇宙似乎在...
George Lucas灵光一闪中形成...
它事实上与电影大相径庭
故事原先是关于Luke Starkiller
Starkiller在根本上是父亲...
双胞胎是他的孩子
最终发展为双胞胎之一...
与反派父亲的故事
我写了很多草稿
把故事翻来覆去...
设法找到合适的一种
尽管他们把故事设置在遥远的星系...
星球大战的人物包含了
神话传说中的经典原型
For luck.
Lucas花了两年多的时间写剧本...
仔细拼凑各部分
写剧本的时候
常常要移动人物
就像一套棋子
有主要角色...
有次要角色 有同伙...
有坏人还有党羽
你要移动他们
想办法把故事编好
为了让纸上的人物变成三维活物...
Lucas雇佣了插画家Ralph McQuarrie.
在创作科幻与奇幻故事时...
与一位插画家工作十分有益...
使大脑里的东西形象化...
这样我就不用花大量时间...
描述所有的小细节
只要画一张画就行了
我与Ralph一同坐下...
我告诉他人物是什么
长什么样子...
让后他会画一系列草图
我看过草图跟他说
''不 我要这样 我要那样
眼睛要大一点
我要他小点''
有时候会完全不同
电影里最古老的原型人物...
就是星球大战的英雄
Luke Skywalker
神话故事中没有任何特定人物...
直接与Luke Skywalker有联系
Luke Skywalker是一个英雄
他更像是众多...
传说与童话书中的普遍典型
例如Joseph Campbell写的『千面英雄』
Luke Skywalke是个狠角色...
因为那一类型角色的天性...
他们得是普通人
他们得让我们观众产生同感
He was the person
that we went on this journey with.
Luke Skywalker的有力造型...
注定能捕捉到一代影迷的想象...
要是他由Kenny Baker扮演
还会那么受欢迎吗?
我本把Luke Skywalker写成一个侏儒...
农场里的所有人
the aunt and the uncle
那一群人
都是小矮人
That boy is our last hope.
No, there is another.
双胞胎和他们父亲的故事
这自始至终都没改动
有一次 我让双胞胎中的女孩当英雄...
最终 我把它改成男性人物
- I'm not going anywhere.
- They're gonna execute her.
You said you didn't want to just wait
to be captured. Now you want to stay?
Marching into the detention area
is not what I had in mind.
- But they're gonna kill her.
- Better her than me.
讲述故事的方法之一就是
设置两个主要人物...
他们与对方完全相反
这样可以形成对比
Luke是一个理想主义的
天真农场男孩...
他即将走向世界
心中有一点慌乱
要承担责任
里面有个长者
一个向导和教育者...
带他启程 给与忠告
You must learn the ways of the Force
if you're to come with me to Alderaan.
Alderaan?
通常还要设置一个同伙...
他的道德观等方面都与英雄相反
他们经常会意见不合
在这部电影中...
主题之一是同情与互助
无私对自私
一个人物十分无私...
I'm Luke Skywalker.
I'm here to rescue you.
另一个人物十分自私
I ain't in this for your revolution,
and I'm not in it for you, Princess.
I expect to be well paid.
I'm in it for the money.
我把他们放在一起
所以他们遇到情况时...
总会意见分歧
Han Solo是我们都希望能成为的人物
我认为大多数人
都觉得自己像Luke Skywalker...
但是我们都情愿当Han Solo
Lucas起先把Han Solo构想成...
一个巨大的绿皮怪物
长着大鳃
被Wookiees养大
Solo在早年与Chewbacca交了朋友...
他们在一起成为了星际海盗
Han Solo本来是一个穷凶极恶的人物
他本来是一个怪物
或是古怪的外星人
我最终决定他是人类...
这样他们三人间就能有更多关系
这就是Chewbacca是外星同伙的缘由
星球大战的几个人物
来源于神化传说...
Han Solo的同伙Chewbacca...
是受到了个人关系的启发
Chewbacca的原始灵感来自我的狗 Indiana
我写剧本的时候
她一直坐在我身边
她坐在我车里
当我的副驾驶员
她坐在车里的时候跟我一样高
她是阿拉斯加爱斯基摩狗
她非常大
我觉得那情景很有趣
当我想为Han Solo找外星副驾驶员时...
我立马就想到了Indiana.
有一张30年代的图片...
毛茸茸像猿的动物 George很喜欢
我说道 ''把他的脸画的更像松鼠或猫''
我们想画某一属动物的特征...
而不是某一个特定的动物品种
一开始 我们把他画得像狐猴
之后 我画了一个下面长了乳房的生物
我去除了乳房
因为它不是女性
我加上了子弹带
给了他武器
电影制作的每一方面...
几乎都是协力完成的
星球大战的人物创作也是如此
我脑中产生一个主意...
我要某个人物 外星人 或者场景是什么样子
然后 我会告诉设计师我的想法...
让他画下来 使之形象化
- I got him!
- Great, kid. Don't get cocky.
接着 我要把画稿交给美术部门...
或是道具部门 或是化妆部门...
他们会把它转化成...
真实的 机械的 塑料的或毛制的实体
在那时候 我们并没有能力做动画...
所以我决定 Chewbacca将由...
一个高大的人穿着外套表演
他们说那东西毛多个大 就这么多
我们到了那里 参观了一下...
Ralph McQuarrie站在那里
拿着一张尼安德塔人的图画
区别在于Ralph让Chewie穿上了...
百慕大短裤和背心
I had no choice.
What are you doing?
Trust him!
为了让Chewbacca的面部表情可信...
Lucas求助于行业中少数的专家之一
我与Stuart Freeborn合作
他在(太空奥德赛)2001里制作了猿人
我认为他的作品很棒
而且 既然我们有Wookiee...
我说道 ''我们要用2001里的相同技术制作猿人''
356 第四次
他把Ralph的画稍作改动...
并让Peter Mayhew扮演
他的身体结构
他的行走方式
他的眼睛
测量他的实际骨架结构
去制作戏服...
和能机械运动的脸
改变了设计
现实情况改变了设计
当你有个设计思路
想把它投入现实...
大多数时候
特别是在早期...
一切都会改动
现在 有了数字技术
构思了某个东西...
设计了某个东西
让其原汁原味地出来就容易多了
但是在从前
没有这回事
We seem to be made to suffer.
It's our lot in life.
给了我星球大战开头灵感的电影之一...
是黑泽明的『战国英豪』
讲的是两个处于封建日本社会底层的农民
Matashichi, this is hell.
It's the end!
If we're going to die,
let's die together.
与将军和公主同行
贵族阶级的人
Just prepare the rice.
Shut up. I can't take it anymore.
You can stuff your orders.
故事是从他们的角度讲述的
I'm not one of them.
从最低的社会阶层来看这场冒险...
这场发生在最宏大的国际外交层面上的冒险
他们被设计成一种Mutt and Jeff...
- Don't kick the stones.
- You stop grabbing my leg.
Abbott and Costello Laurel and Hardy
对电影的戏剧性调剂
I've just about had enough of you.
Go that way.
You'll be malfunctioning within a day,
you nearsighted scrap pile.
And don't let me catch you
following me, begging for help...
because you won't get it.
要喜剧性调剂有效果
你得创造两个迥然不同的人物...
我设置了一个小astrodroid...
与人类没有任何相似之处...
另一个是更高雅的翻译droid...
它被赋予人形...
被编程 使之能更好地与人类交流
I am C-3PO,
human-cyborg relations.
This is my counterpart, R2-D2.
Hello.
我要为3PO找一个非常高雅复杂的设计构思...
因为3PO来自于一个更高雅复杂的环境
I'm not much more than an interpreter
and not very good at telling stories.
3PO的早期构思
受到了『大都会』中机器人的启发
3PO要看起来像『大都会』中的机器人
不过是个男子...
我画了一幅
3PO和R2穿越沙漠的画...
你可以在其背景看到他们的太空舱
创造3PO最困难的事情之一...
就是得做一个完全中性的脸...
这样我才能让它读入不同情景中...
表达的各种情绪
我雇了一个女雕刻家
她做了一系列头像...
设法做一个完全中性的头像...
上面完全没有任何情绪
我要它所有的反应...
都来源于它周围的环境和情节...
如果他开心
你就能从他的脸上读出喜悦
如果他伤心
你就能从他的脸上读出悲伤
完全不被他的脸部构造所歪曲
Don't call me a mindless philosopher,
you overweight glob of grease.
Come out,
before somebody sees you.
我本来要他像个...
油嘴滑舌的二手车经销商或推销员
他要更像个推销员
总是想讨好别人
总是说大道理
-Can you speak Bocce?
-Of course. It's like a second language.
-All right. Shut up. I'll take this one.
-Shutting up, sir.
当Tony Daniels来了之后
他是个好演员
他操着英国口音
我爱上了那口音
我试过很多不同的人
我试过二手汽车经销商
我试过推销员
无一奏效 除了Tony他那种烦人的英国管家
到星球大战摄影棚的第一天...
他们才刚好完成戏服...
我穿上之后...
我对场记员说
''请你拿块偏光板来...
把它举高''
通过那小眼睛
And through the little eyes, I looked
at a little Polaroid of myself...
and that's where I really learned
totally what I looked like for the day.
If I told you half the things
I've heard about this Jabba the Hutt...
you'd probably
short-circuit.
我们首先见到3PO时
他通体金黄
摄影棚里摆亮闪闪的东西很危险...
因为它会反射所有东西
从外面开着的补给车...
到端茶小姐 到护士
而且 George的世界充满了
粪料 骨头和尘土...
所以3PO满身污泥
完全违背他的本性 当然
This oil bath is going to feel so good.
I've got such a bad case of dust
contamination I can barely move.
他总是在结尾时被擦亮
这在星球大战中...
是一种演出结束 大步行走之装
总是被擦得亮闪闪的
3PO有趣的一点是
他没有灵魂
他被编程要以特定方式思考
并富有同情心...
但他并不知道那是什么意思
Chewie, take the professor in the back
and plug him into the hyperdrive.
Sometimes I just don't
understand human behavior.
有时候他会很沮丧
有许多类人品质...
但是他没有可独自思考的主要部位
Darth Vader 另一方面
他变得越来越机械化...
他丧失越来越多的能力
甚至不能像人一样思考
起先 有好父亲和坏父亲
好父亲是Anakin Starkiller
坏父亲是Darth Vader
在写剧本的时候
那两个人物稍微变换了位置
我思来想去
最终他们合并成了一个人物
Obi-Wan never told you
what happened to your father.
He told me enough.
He told me you killed him.
I am your father.
将古代传说中好坏父亲合并的决定...
创造了一个难以忘怀的人物...
由于他处于人和机器之间的本性
此人物得到了提升
Darth Vader弃人从机器...
他不断丧失自己的灵魂
丧失自己的人性...
这是主题
Darth Vader这人物
Lucas的最初设计构思...
来自于阿拉伯半岛的贝都因武士
George进来向我描述Darth Vader...
一个迎着风 飘忽不定的轮廓
十分黑暗 幽灵般的人物
他可能戴着一个大头盔
就像中古时期的日本武士
McQuarrie很快意识到星际旅行...
会影响到他的人物设计
他的解决方案成了Darth Vader最险恶的特点之一
他要从一个太空船而来...
在走道中炸开一个洞...
从而进入另一个太空船
我开始为他担心...
不穿太空服而穿过真空太空
George不太情愿地说道...
''那就去给他加上呼吸面罩''
我每做一件事
做到一定程度 他就会说...
''好了 就这样
我们继续去做其它事'
Darth Vader就此了结...
电影里的他与我画的差不多
George Lucas的成就
与托尔金一样
他创造了值得纪念的人物
You've taken
your first step into a larger world.
我认为他碰触到了
非常有力和根本的东西
I'm not afraid.
You will be.
今日想起星球大战
电影最初播放的25年后...
你会记不起那些特技
但是你记得那些人物
Darth Vader和Han Solo...
和Yoda和Luke Skywalker还有Chewbacca.
人物留了下来
Why, you stuck-up, half-witted...
scruffy-looking nerf herder!
Who's scruffy-lookin'?
平心而论 你要从George...
对于人性和电影理解的才华讲起
There's nothing for me here now.
I want to learn the ways of the Force
and become a Jedi like my father.
这些神话经受了时间的考验...
被观众们所喜爱
因为其中的人物
在构思和扮演上都非常美妙
Great shot, kid!
That was one in a million!
Remember, the Force
will be with you always.
Han, can you reach my lightsaber?
Can anyone?
That's my face.
I thought that was
a deer's ass in here.
Cut!
Cheer them on, guys.
Cheer them on.
Try and climb up,
get back down again.
Beat the-- out of them!
And cut.
他是你最爱的坏人
他是个切实的反派角色
它要么让你害怕 要么让你激动
I find your lack of faith disturbing.
那呼吸声让人胆寒
第三部在根本上讲的是...
Anakin Skywalker如何变成了Darth Vader...
我认为大家都在等待这故事
这是Anakin终结的开头
You don't know the power
of the dark side.
the return of
Darth Vader
我回过头来拍前传讲述...
Anakin Skywalker如何变成了Darth Vader
是因为这故事很有趣 很有娱乐性...
是因为它讲述了
一个好人变坏的历程
他从一个伶俐聪明...
富有爱心和同情心的小男孩...
发展成一个细心 刻苦...
但野心勃勃的Padawan learner...
他觉得因为自己who feels that
because he's better at being a Jedi...
and his Jedi skills
than most of the otherJedi...
所以应该进步得更深更快
In some ways--
a lot of ways--
I'm really ahead of him.
等他进步了 他无法控制自己的脾气...
他想控制事物的贪欲
这使他走向了毁灭
他陷入原力黑暗面经过了周密安排...
源自于十分具有人性的事情
他陷入爱河
他即将成为一个父亲...
他嫉妒了
我不清楚
我们把事情混成一团...
因为我们都年轻天真
无法退一步...
然后说 ''哦 不 没关系的''
Put the ship down!
Don't let your personal feelings
get in the way!
Anakin从始到终的问题就是...
他不愿意放手
I don't want things to change.
But you can't stop the change.
当他不断寻求更多力量
去改变人们的命运...
让那些人按他的意思过
试图拯救所爱之人的贪欲...
变成了控制宇宙的能力
第三部现在缺少一部分...
那是第三部关键的一部分
也是大家一直想看到的...
就是Anakin Skywalker穿上suit的回归
面部 构思...
Ralph McQuarrie早前的灵感还在...
我们试图忠于原作
看到原始头盔后...
我们发现它的形状不对称
我们有机会把它做得更对称...
这就是我们要做的
所有细节都在这板上...
所以我们花了很多时间
把这一侧弄漂亮
我把它扫描进机器
我在电脑里把它翻过来...
我现在正在切割右边脸
今天结束前 我们有望把两半合起来
看看效果
那将是人们第一次见到对称的Darth Vader
我们开始做头盔了
明天要注模
肩膀做好了
头部也在做了
几个星期后 这些部分将被拼成Darth Vader
这样很好
但我们还要做boxes
我们要开始做fittings
起初 是一件米色的suit...
看上去一点都不吓人
但是一种怀旧之情涌上心头...
我不晓得即将会有什么感觉
I've been waiting for you, Obi-Wan.
We meet again at last.
他们本可以
随便找个高个子就混过去...
不过我又求又请
他们也十分好心地...
给我量身定做了一套Darth Vader suit
把头盔罩上...
里面看上去太瘦了
我不晓得你能不能看清楚
在这边加上一个小管子...
再加一块辅料
整个轮廓就出来了 也把脸填满了
也更像我们记忆中的形象
这种事情很怪
我们总是在发现
那些我们以为已经会了的东西
同时
我们要做一个...
Anakin和Obi-Wan两人
互相斗剑的场景
这是个十分困难的事情
这(两人)是好朋友
你知道 这是他的良师益友...
他们的友谊破碎了
Anakin就让它发生了
Obi-Wan似乎总是对那小孩心存戒心...
向他奄奄一息的师父Qui-Gon做了保证...
他保证要把小孩训练成Jedi
并照顾他...
他做到了 我认为
尽他所能
在斗剑中
你要学上千种招数
这很困难 你还得记住它们
你必须得牢牢记住
不然头就会挨劈
手指头?
每个场景都要重复打很多遍...
要做得尽可能完美...
十分累人
我们要重做一遍
很辛苦 不过一天结束时
我们俩都会很满足
那些家伙十分投入...
一个人犯了错误
boom-暂停
他们都没事
有说有笑
boom-过几秒钟
他们又练起来了
他们每天都能持续好几个小时
Ewan一直都是个好剑客...
不过Hayden富有运动细胞
他打得也很好
这一场的特别之处在于
他们要对打
所以他们都很卖力...
每天都把常规做完
努力超过对方
And that leads into this.
They've done more layers
of the silicone...
and then we've done
a fiberglass jacket around it.
We've then taken all of that off
so we could get the original shape out.
So we now have an empty shell, which
is going to be our Darth Vader helmet...
which now Adam is about to start
laying up in polyester--in fiberglass.
新鲜出炉 Darth Vader头盔
看起来蛮不赖的
我认为Hayden一定会很激动
扮演Darth Vader
进入Darth Vader
这是最酷的部分
给Hayden再试穿一次
拍到电影上
接着它就成为回忆了
我们组所有人
都想参与制作这个
我们跟他去摄影棚的那天
他走进镜头...
你看着他闪闪发光...
想到 ''这真是件神奇的事情''
带我们回到了过去
很久很久以前
在一个遥远的星系
星球大战传奇的下一篇章
绝地归来
善与恶的战斗愈演愈烈
加入这一群人的冒险...
Luke Skywalker...
Han Solo...
Leia公主...
Lando Calrissian...
Chewbacca...
C-3PO和R2-D2...
还有Darth Vader
一次去外星世界的旅程
It's a trap.
一场对压迫的反抗斗争
一部英雄与恶棍的史诗
一场同宇宙一样大的冒险
绝地归来
将在你星系的指定影院上映
激光剑的诞生
40年代的海盗电影和浪漫主义电影
绝对影响了星球大战
『罗宾汉历险记』(1938)
Errol Flynn演的那种电影
在那一段时间 电影院里全是...
奇幻 动作冒险流派的电影
For luck.
星球大战的前提是
它为一部浪漫主义奇幻电影...
富有神话中的浪漫主义传统...
你知道的 『亚瑟王』
打斗的浪漫一面...
富有骑士精神和荣耀之类的
为了发扬一群和平卫士...
他们高于一切
受人尊敬 有决定权...
为星系带来和平...
我需要能和绝地相称的武器
Your father wanted you to have this
when you were old enough...
but your uncle wouldn't allow it.
- What is it?
- Your father's lightsaber.
This is the weapon of a Jedi knight.
Not as clumsy or random
as a blaster.
An elegant weapon...
for a more civilized age.
它更像是一段简约时期的象征...
那时候帝国尚未掌权
而是由荣耀来统治
电影中 它不只是一种实际武器
更是一种象征
Hokey religions and ancient weapons
are no match for a blaster at your side.
You don't believe
in the Force, do you?
原始构思是绝地用剑打斗
之后 我想换成更有未来主义的剑...
所以我把它换成了激光剑...
给了它一种科技优势
在那射线枪横流的时代里...
它可以偏转射线
既然前提是绝地用它们防身...
不是用来进攻 而是防御...
在射线枪世界里用激光剑...
作为防御武器再适合不过
It started out as a kind of
Oriental form of swordplay...
where there was a lot of honor involved
and a lot of skill and craft...
and higher spiritual meaning
to the sword fight.
So they were very simple.
In the beginning...
the first film, Episode IV...
it was a fight between
a very old man...
and a man who was only partially
a man and mostly a mechanical being.
So it wasn't really
much of a sword fight at all.
When I left, I was but a learner.
Now I am the master.
Only a master of evil, Darth.
激光剑最初是
四乘五相机的闪光附件
我们把圆形的闪光部分拆下来
用它来做激光剑
George坚持说那些剑...
十分 十分重
重到不能单手拿
我们一直得用两只手
就像一把Excalibur
有40,50磅重
非常的强大
里面蕴含了大量能量
挥动它们的时候
感觉很沉重...
因为它们撞到一起的时候...
会产生巨大的爆炸 等等等等
到后来...
我们让激光剑斗
变得更快更激烈...
因为Luke的剑艺越来越高
所以 我们慢慢把东方式的双手持剑...
变为不时用单手持剑
继续发展下去...
成了双手和单手混用
不过起先
你必须用两只手拿激光剑...
因为要挥动大量的能量
You see? You can do it.
I call it luck.
In my experience,
there's no such thing as luck.
激光剑的效果
基本上是根旋转的棒子...
上面涂了银幕材料...
这样它就能以多倍亮度...
把光源反射回去
问题是 如果你把它移出一定范围...
它就不再反光...
变回了旋转的棒子
我们在表面缠上反光胶带
这样它就能发光照亮演员
这方法没奏效
他们会打坏激光剑
之后 我们采用了涂反光材料的棍子
再后来 我们更加...
精通于制作斗剑
我们采用了无反光材料的剑...
我们决定不再通过镜头拍摄光...
和很多其他的过程...
这样我们拍摄打斗时可以轻松些
118BT 第二镜 A相机
And action!
我原以为他们以后
会把卡通剑身放进去
不过 如果你在斗剑...
你就不会停手
你需要找东西来敲
每一把激光剑都是半真半画的
我们需要真的棒子
来告诉我们剑身的位置
有时候我们会用短剑身
因为他们要近战...
会打到场景里的东西
有时候我们不用剑身...
因为剑会在镜头中展开...
或者他们的动作太过复杂...
无法用剑来模拟
我们之后会把剑加进去
但这需要很仔细地追踪轨迹...
计算出剑身的位置
再后来 到了第二第三部(V VI)...
他们认为当场拍摄得不偿失...
全部在后期完成
我们仍然用一小段棒子...
这样就有个东西可以打
这多亏于特技的进步...
而不是其他方面
我们的转描技术越来越娴熟...
早期画面-转描之前
未重合的转描
我们用了更先进的技术...
更近的转描 仍然未重合
来更容易地跟踪那些剑...
复制下来
制作激光剑
最终画面
You are beaten.
It is useless to resist.
Don't let yourself be destroyed
as Obi-Wan did.
尽管在拍摄的时候
激光剑看上去有些蹩脚...
在后期制作时
他们给其上了应有的样子
当然还有
Ben Burtt出色的声音效果
第一部电影中激光剑的声效
被交给了Ben Burtt
Ben从一开头...
我写剧本的时候就开工了
我告诉他我需要R2的声音
我需要Darth Vader呼吸的声音
我需要射线枪的声音
我需要激光剑的声音
我为这电影制作的
第一个声效是激光剑
我记得在当时
我在墙上看了Ralph McQuarrie的一些作品
画的是Luke在电影结尾斗剑
他们拿着激光剑
我立马就想到了
我觉得我知道它们会发什么声音
在电影放映室里
那些放映机会发出嗡嗡声
他们不在运转 只是闲置着
马达在那边发着...
一种魔幻神秘的嗡鸣声...
某方面来说 我觉得很悦耳
我想道 ''这大概就是激光剑的声音''
Your powers are weak, old man.
You can't win, Darth.
If you strike me down...
I shall become more powerful
than you can possibly imagine.
我当时还找了些其他元素
我有一台录音机
话筒线坏了
包裹物脱落了
我在公寓里经过电视机的时候...
显像管里的嗡鸣声
通过破线传了出来
产生蜂鸣 我说道
''这蜂鸣好听 听上去很危险''
我把蜂鸣声录了下来
健全的人通常不会要嗡鸣声
这一次 嗡鸣声就是答案
当然 我要录入声音...
把剑掠过发出的嗖嗖声去掉
他花了大半年时间制作那些声音
我首次加入激光剑的声效的地方
是在一段电影的临时剪辑
对它没有多少评论
但我从此明白
没有评论 那就是很棒
那就是通过测试
Impressive.
Most impressive.
最终 激光剑的声音...
因为我们要富有能量的感觉...
是几种不同声音的组合
从哗哗响的真空吸尘器...
到一种击打干冰的碰撞声
那之后我们做了改进
因为武器移动得更快了...
最新电影中我们有双头激光剑
但都是基于相同的录音
There's nothing you could have done,
had you been there.
You'd have been killed too...
and the droids would now be
in the hands of the Empire.
I want to come with you to Alderaan.
There's nothing for me here now.
I want to learn the ways of the Force
and become a Jedi like my father.
在每一部中 从 IV V和VI...
我不断改善剑斗...
因为我假设Luke正成为...
更强的剑客
他在学更多的东西
但与此同时...
他并没有按Jedi传统的方式进行训练
AJedi uses the Force
for knowledge and defense...
never for attack.
- But tell me why I can't--
- No. There is no why.
Nothing more
will I teach you today.
在Empire Strikes Back中...
反派人物和正派人物首次交手
所以 这是场大仗...
Luke已经足够精通...
可以与Darth Vader交手
所以 这是场稍微一边倒的剑斗...
Vader稍胜一筹
在这场打斗戏中...
Luke并不知道Vader是他父亲
他以为自己在打仇敌
所以他尽全力地去打
他以为自己在打杀父仇人...
打杀死Obi-Wan Kenobi的人...
打宇宙中邪恶附身的人
在下一场打斗中...
两人不分伯仲
再下一场
Return of the Jedi...
他知道自己在与父亲对打
I see you have constructed
a new lightsaber.
他知道皇帝是幕后黑手
Your skills are complete.
他也知道他在处理的问题...
比剑斗大得多
Indeed you are powerful,
as the emperor has foreseen.
所以这场剑斗更注重
于剑斗时的感情背景...
而不是剑斗本身
Never!
这是电影的高潮
而不是高科技战争 死星爆炸之类的...
这是更个人的剑斗
父子之间的较量
然后我们拍摄了前传...
其中Jedi in their full flower...
按过去的方式斗剑
训练有素的绝地
我们要把他们的剑斗动作做得更快...
更复杂 更有攻击性
我们延续了下去
Brave of you, boy.
But I would have thought
you had learned your lesson.
I am a slow learner.
Anakin!
比起第IV V和VI
剑斗变得更加残忍
Fought well you have,
my old Padawan.
This is just the beginning.
一个基于一个
因为剑斗变得更加私人...
直到第三部
这是一场非常私人的较量
这一场 他们要殊死搏斗
所以时间很长
现场 "Star Wars Episode III"
两个人物间的区别是
Obi-Wan经验更丰富...
但Anakin更强大
很不错
Thanks, everybody.
You know, I'm here today
as Luke Skywalker...
but I'm also here
to talk about Sprint.
As you can see, you stand to save
up to 1 7 cents a month...
over the more
dependable providers.
Luke Skywalker与Han Solo
救出了公主...
摧毁了死星
但他们的故事还没结束
有史以来最火电影的制作者们...
带给你星球大战传奇的下一部
帝国反击战
我们英雄的故事延续...
Luke Skywalker...
Princess Leia...
Han Solo...
C-3PO...
R2-D2...
和Chewbacca.
并介绍Lando Calrissian
这部史诗包含了浪漫...
包含了英雄和恶棍
他们穿过杳无人迹的真空
来到了未知的世界
对抗压迫的银河奥德赛
星球大战传奇的新冒险
帝国反击战
明年夏天在你的星系上映
I'm Luke Skywalker.
I'm here to rescue you.
它是有史以来最受欢迎的太空冒险
''Exciting''is hardly
the word I would choose.
它是好莱坞历史上最先锋的传奇之一
There'll be no one
to stop us this time.
它以一种不可抗力捕获了想象力...
You've taken your first step
into a larger world.
并把三名年轻演员变成了超级明星
- I got him!
- Great kid! Don't get cocky.
星球大战获得成功后
纷纷而来的机会...
改变了我的整个人生
它是一则奇妙的寓言
I'll never turn to the dark side.
It's Geroge's vision
and he truly is a visual man
in a profound way.
但是星球大战三部曲...
不止改变了我们视电影的方式
它改变了电影拍摄的方式
You must unlearn
what you have learned.
George造就了许多东西...
其改变了我们所知的(电影)行业
We did it!
一则星系童话的成功...
超越了任何人最狂野的梦想
The Force will be with you always.
我本打算永远都不去拍热门电影
这不是我的安排
我并没期望星球大战会如此热门
但它成为了一种现象
=梦想的帝国=
星球大战三部曲的故事
很难回忆起星球大战之前的时代
那时的世界是另一幅景象
那时候没有手机和个人电脑
互联网的出现遥遥无期
就连家庭电视游戏
还有一大段路要走
- 太空竞赛已经结束
- 对一个人来说这是一小步
美国人感到深陷于现状
那时候处于通货膨胀...
石油价格上涨...
国民对他们的英雄和领导人冷嘲热讽
我不是骗子
在我们国家 水门(丑闻)撕开了我们
此外我们还在打越南战争...
前所未有地在分裂国家
那是我们历史中可怕的十年
充斥着风暴和暴力
在大银幕上 好莱坞的看法同样惊心
1970年代的早期电影
gritty且常为悲观...
反映了美国的社会与政治剧变
老式英雄已逝...
打破一切规则的顽固反英雄
统治着银幕
在60年代末期
the Warners the Zanucks...
那些首先建立制片厂的人...
都退休了 他们把制片厂卖给了公司
有饮料公司还有所有其他行业的
他们根本不知道如何经营制片厂
他们知道的是
销售部门说人们想看这个...
你就去拍那个
他们开始销售电影...
研究人口统计资料之类的东西
他们意识到年轻人
拍给年轻人看的电影有市场...
因为年轻人群占市场的更大部分
持续数十年的制片制度瓦解了
好莱坞的主管们
急切地想接触年轻观众...
到电影学校
来找下一代的电影制作人
- 开拍
- 在这种变革的气氛中...
富有天赋的年轻导演
比如Francis Ford Coppola...
Brian De Palma...
Martin Scorsese...
和Steven Spielberg...
把更多的个人感性带上了银幕
那是个困惑的年代
很多电影制作人要做...
平时做不到的方案
我在正中间被找上了
George是北加州来的不羁少年...
一个独立电影制作者
他总是因为...
自己与好莱坞关系甚少而自豪
出生于加利福尼亚州Modesto...
George Lucas读着冒险故事...
看着电视连续剧长大
上大学的时候
他制作电影的梦想才浮出水面
1963年 他离开Modesto...
去参加南加州大学(USC)的电影班
我当时在USC教书
George上了一门讨论课
我们讨论了他电影制作的早期尝试
我告诉你 从一开始...
George就有独一无二的视角
George能在常规外思考...
你可以从他的学生电影
THX-1138中看出来
THX-1138 4EB
This is Authority.
You will stop where you are.
他拍了一部20分钟的电影
本应是五分钟
You're going for
the emergency switch.
但是他得到了大量认可
打开了教授们的眼睛...
孩子可以做出打破常规...
超越限制的东西
Lucas的专业技术和故事想象力...
赢得了大家的喝彩
他对神化和哲学的兴趣
gave his work an added dimension.
George's style was fantastic.
Incredible.
不管他拍什么...
都比其他作品看上去更个人
从USC毕业后...
Lucas与朋友Francis Ford Coppola合伙...
Coppola在1969年于旧金山
创建了美国西洋镜公司...
一家独立电影公司
我并不打算变得成功
但是我感到...
有能力控制自己的作品...
而不被人篡改
1971年 Lucas导演了THX-1138...
基于他学生电影的影院长片
当华纳兄弟的主管们
观看了成品后...
他们要求Coppola归还$300,000...
the studio had advanced
to develop THX and other projects.
初出茅庐的公司imploded
Lucas得去其他地方找工作
他决定自己包揽大局...
并开了自己的公司
卢卡斯电影有限公司
它旗下的第一个项目...
Lucas选择了『美国风情画』...
an affectionate look at teenage cruising
in the early 1 960s.
- I'm a ready teddy.
- Well, get bent, turkey.
由环球制片厂制片...
此电影宽松地基于...
他在Modesto作为汽车狂热者的个人经历
我原是极端实验主义且强硬...
然后接受了Francis给我的挑战
''我赌你不会拍一部傻乎乎的喜剧''
一部温馨虚幻的喜剧
我说 ''我去试试''
电影只拍摄了28天
成本低于100万美元
合作制片人是也是USC的校友 Gary Kurtz
『美国风情画』的后期制作将近尾声...
我们在旧金山Northpoint电影院
组织了一场放映
我们感觉到观众的反应很积极
但是来自环球制片厂的Ned Tanen十分恼火
他说 ''你眼下不应该把它放给观众看''
我们完全目瞪口呆
他们不理解我的第一部电影
完成后还来干涉它
我的第二部电影也是如此
公司实体进来...
对它胡搞了一番
剪掉了5分钟
在发表『美国风情画』之前...
George Lucas的想象已指向星空
在此期间 他一直在说...
他想拍一部类似于『飞侠哥顿』的
1930年代的太空歌剧
他正经地着手工作
人们说 ''Of all things to pick,
why in the world would you do that?''
I said, ''It's fun to make films
for young people.
It's a chance to
make an impression on them.
I wanna do this.''
With his galactic fairy tale...
Lucas hoped to reinvent
a classic genre.
Among his influences...
were the writings of scholar
and educatorJoseph Campbell...
in which he explored the origins
of myth and world religions.
When Lucas was writing
the script of Star Wars...
he was heavily interested
in Joseph Campbell.
WhatJoseph Campbell
was interested in...
was to see the connections between
the myths of different cultures...
to try to find out
what were the threads...
that tied all these very
disparate cultures together.
I did research to try
to distill everything...
down into motifs
that would be universal.
I attribute most of the success
to the psychological underpinnings...
which had been around
for thousands of years...
and the people still react the same way
to the stories as they always have.
George is nothing
if not a good reporter.
And when he sets out
to do his work...
he starts reporting from
the best sources he can gather.
He brought Campbell
into the process...
of looking at his work
on Star Wars...
and saying, ''Is this right?
Am I getting it down?
Is this the right emphasis?
Is this the right character?''
Joseph Campbell said to me the best
student he ever had was George Lucas.
Like such epics as The Odyssey...
Beowulf...
and The Legend of King Arthur...
Star Wars drew from
a shared pool of mythic archetypes.
You have the youth who's on the
adventure that you can identify with.
You have the swashbuckler.
And you have the damsel.
She may not have the reactions
that are conventional...
however she is in distress.
And you have the wise old man,
who you go and you find him.
And you have
the funnier characters.
I mean, it really adheres
strictly to that form.
It's the traditional,
ritualistic coming-of-age story.
When I went into the mythological
side of what I wanted to do...
that's a key factor with heroes.
By the summer of 1 973...
George Lucas had created a treatment
that he felt was ready to shop around.
Whether anyone would be interested,
that was another story.
The most successful science fiction film
up to that point was 2001 .
Successful then was that
it made about $2 4 million.
Most hit science fiction films
would make about $ 1 6 million...
which was the Planet of the Apes films,
and that sort of thing.
But most science fiction films
would make under $ 1 0 million.
There's no reason to think
that it would do any different.
Star Wars was more
space fantasy than science fiction...
but its galactic setting
made it a tough sell in 1 973.
When I was pitching the film,
all I had was a 1 4-page story treatment.
It was very vague.
Said it was kind of a 1 930s...
action adventure,
Saturday afternoon serial...
based on the kind of Flash Gordon,
Buck Rogers kind of comic book future.
And that's about all
they knew about it.
In the '70s, science fiction
seemed to be...
all about apocalyptic societies
and death and destruction.
Not very inspiring.
We were fighting an uphill battle
with a science fiction project.
George Lucas brought Star Wars
to Universal and United Artists.
Both studios passed
on the project.
But the ambitious young filmmaker
was secretly relieved.
The last thing he wanted was to hand
his dream project to the wrong people.
He didn't care
for the studio system.
He used it because there was no other
way of doing what he needed to do.
Undaunted, Lucas presented
Star Wars to Alan Ladd,Jr....
the new head of creative affairs
at 20th Century Fox.
Ladd, a former producer, was able to
recognize potential in the filmmaker...
if not necessarily the film.
We had a meeting,
and George said...
''I've been thinking about
this thing called Star Wars. ''
And he told me about it.
I said, ''That sounds terrific.''
The technology part of the whole
thing was completely over my head.
But I just believed in him
and his genius.
I sort of recognized
from American Graffiti...
that he really was a genius,
so I just flew with it.
He understood what talent was.
He respected talent
and he was able to say...
''I think this guy's talented.
I think we're gonna invest in him. ''
So, Alan Ladd,Jr. invested in me.
He did not invest in the movie.
And it paid off.
In 1 973, Ladd's investment
in George Lucas provedjustified.
American Graffiti was finally
released to rave reviews...
and became the third-highest
grossing picture of the year.
It went on to earn more than
$ 1 00 million worldwide.
American Graffiti showed
a very human center and a huge heart...
that George has always had.
I think that surprised
a lot of people.
With a preliminary deal
for Star Wars in place...
Lucas began writing
his screenplay in 1 97 4.
It proved more ambitious
than he had first imagined.
The filmmaker was able to
distill his idea down to its essence--
an epic battle between
a heroic Rebel Alliance...
and an evil Galactic Empire.
The chief villain, Darth Vader,
was there practically from the start.
But it took time to come up with
Star Wars's three main heroes--
a plucky young princess
named Leia Organa...
the fearless Corellian smuggler
known as Han Solo...
and most important,
an idealistic farm boy...
whose original name
was Luke Starkiller.
Over the course ofhis adventure...
Luke trains to become
a Jedi knight...
deriving his power from a mystical
energy known as ''the Force. ''
But along the way, the script
went through radical changes.
At one point, Luke was
a 60-year-old general...
and Han Solo
had green skin and gills.
Even the concept of the Force
had yet to be fully realized.
Instead, there was
the Kaiburr Crystal...
a sort of galactic Holy Grail.
The concept of the Force was
an important one in the story.
The difficulty is...
trying to create
a religious-spiritual concept...
that works in a very simple way
without heavy exposition...
or without it seeming
to pull down the story.
It got to be a very fat script,
about 200 pages.
And the story
had gotten away from me.
So, the only way I could
cope with it was to say...
''I'll take the first third-- the first
act-- and I'll make that into a movie.''
But I'd written all this other stuff.
I'd spent a year writing this story.
I said, ''I'm not gonna throw away
two thirds of my year...
and say,
'This is all I can afford at this point.
This is the only money I'm gonna get
is to do this one movie.'''
I put it on the shelf.I said, ''By hook
or by crook, I will finish this movie. ''
But Star Wars
wouldn't be cheap.
To get the Fox board of directors
to approve the necessary budget...
Lucas needed
something dramatic.
He hired Ralph McQuarrie, a conceptual
design artist who had worked for Boeing.
I'd seen some ofhis paintings.
I thought he was brilliant.
I said, ''I want you to do some
paintings of these scenes I've done...
so that the studio can get a picture
of what I'm talking about.''
When I turned in the script, I had
about five or six drawings to say...
''This is what it's gonna look like. ''
He had a concept
for a big spectacular visual...
and it didn't come across
in the script.
So I tried to give it scale...
juxtaposing the tiny little figures...
with the great,
spectacular backgrounds.
George would say, ''Don't worry
about how we're going to do it.
Wejust want an impression of what the
scenes would look like on the screen. ''
McQuarrie's artwork won over
the Fox board of directors...
who soon approved a budget
ofjust over $8 million.
With only the first part
ofhis Star Wars saga being made...
Lucas also needed to think
about the future.
But his prior dealings with major
studios had taught him to be cautious.
When I made the deal
for Star Wars...
originally I made the deal before
American Graffiiti had even come out.
'Cause Alan Ladd had seen American
Graffiiti and said, ''I'll make a deal.''
But he made a very--
you're gonna make X number
of dollars and this kind of thing.
It was like a one-page memo.
When it came up to doing the contract
for the film, about a year later...
I knew that what I really had to do
was to protect the unwritten part--
the other two parts of the script.
All of a sudden,
Graffiti comes out...
and it's a big huge, smash success.
So his agent came back
and said, ''Hey, look.
This guy has made
this huge successful movie.
Don't you think we should get more than
a couple hundred thousand dollars...
for writing, directing
and producing a movie?''
I said, ''Yeah. I think
he should get more. ''
I was very careful to say, ''I don't want
more money. I don't want more points.
I don't want anything financial.
But I do want the right
to make these sequels.''
I was working on the assumption
every filmmaker works on...
which is the film
will be a disaster...
and that it won't be promoted
and it'll just die a horrible death.
And it'll be very hard to get
these next two movies made.
George said, ''I'd like
a big slice of the merchandising. ''
Up until that time, merchandising
had been relatively unknown.
When I took over the licensing,
I simply said...
''I'm gonna be able to make T-shirts.
I'm gonna be able to make posters...
and I'm gonna be able to sell this
movie, even though the studio won't. ''
So, I managed to get control of pretty
much everything that was left over...
that the studio
didn't really care about.
George was enormously farsighted,
and the studio wasn't...
because they didn't know
that the world was changing.
George did know the world was changing.
He changed it.
With his Star Wars contract
completed...
George Lucas
now needed a rebel force...
up to the challenge
of production.
In the summer of 1 975...
he founded the visual effects company
Industrial Light & Magic.
There was no special effects
companies in those days...
and the studios'special effects
department had been disbanded.
Part of that was because
of the expense...
and part of it was
that the American taste...
the culture had gone toward
very realistic-looking films.
We approached the visual effects
as a grand experiment, saying...
''Can we do this with a lot of people
who work on architectural models...
and in commercials and have never made
feature films before?''
We were kind oflike
a weird kind of fraternity...
of robotic photography nuts
or something like that.
I mean, this was a big movie for Fox.
We were doing commercials.
We all dreamed
about doing a feature...
and this was like
the dream come true.
So, Star Wars came along
atjust the perfect time for us.
We moved into a big empty
warehouse in Van Nuys...
right near the Van Nuys Airport
and basically started from scratch.
I mean, it was empty. In the early days,
you used to park your car inside.
There was no camera equipment,
no rooms to speak of.
Supervising at ILM
was John Dykstra...
an effects cameraman who had worked
under Douglas Trumbull...
on films like Silent Running.
I was essentially to be responsible for
doing the visual effects for the film.
We took the concept of motion control,
which is essentially an old concept...
ofbeing able to duplicate camera motion
through more than one pass...
so that you can generate
multiple elements of film...
and we made it production-savvy
by tying it into a computer...
which was, at that point,
custom-built microprocessors.
There were no PCs.
You didn't go buy a PC.
We built them from scratch.
At the same time the camera system
was being built...
another team began constructing
model spaceships.
I was one of the early hires.
They had a small art department.
There were some concept models made
out of cardboard and model kit pieces.
There were some storyboards
and some concept illustrations...
thatJoeJohnston had done.
There were some paintings
that Ralph McQuarrie had done.
Everything came
either from my sketches...
or Ralph's paintings and drawings...
and any input
that George might have.
There wasn't a lot of
outside influences on Star Wars.
George wanted it to look like
you could actually see the rivets...
so you could see the logic
ofhow it was made.
I was originally hired
to work on the Death Star...
the 40 foot by--
What was it? 40-by-80 feet or
40-by-60 feet or something like that.
Nobody wanted thejob, because you had
to spend a lot of time on your knees.
Everybody sort of cross-trained
and worked in different techniques.
That was different
than the Hollywood system...
that had very strict union rules.
But there was no way this work
could be done that way...
or no way that the Hollywood unions
could understand what we were doing.
With preproduction
gaining momentum...
Lucas next began the process
of casting his galactic opus.
He shared the audition stage
with his friend, Brian De Palma...
who was seeking actors
for the Stephen King shocker Carrie.
We were both making these movies
and casting at the same time...
so we decided to combine
our efforts.
I've made movies with very young people
that have no track record...
so I have to discover them.
Pick them and then test them
and go through them and have readings.
It takes a long time. I spent probably
six or seven months casting Star Wars.
That's a long process to sit
in a little room and interview people.
And I interviewed
thousands of people.
In casting the male leads,
Luke Starkiller and Han Solo...
Lucas looked for
individual screen presence...
as well as chemistry
between performers.
Action.
It checks out again.
There's no mistake.
- You can't find Organa Major?
- I found it. It's just not there.
I found it.
It's just not there.
What's left of it
is contaminated.
That's it there.
Look at those radiation readouts.
It's impossible.
-I've never seen anything like it.
-The Empire must have gotten here first.
The planet has been
completely blown away.
For the pivotal role of Luke...
Lucas needed an actor who could
project both intelligence and integrity.
She's part of the royal family.
They won't get anything out of her.
She knows the power of mind control.
She's part of the royal family.
They won't get any information from her.
She knows the art of mind control.
Twenty-four-year-old Mark Hamill was
a familiar face on television.
A newcomer to films, his wholesome,
easygoing manner fit the part perfectly.
I can remember a line
from the screen test...
which I don't think
ever will leave me.
Luke says, ''But we can't turn back.
Fear is their greatest defense.
I doubt the security is any greater
than it was on Aquilae or Sullust...
and what there is is most likely
directed towards a large-scale assault.''
Fear is their greatest defense.
I doubt the security is much greater
than on Aquilae or Sullust...
and what there is is most likely
directed towards a large-scale assault.
I read that line and I thought,
''Who talks like this?''
So I just did it sincerely.
How many more systems
must get blown away...
before you have no place to hide
and are forced to fight?
Don't you realize what's going on?
Kid, you take the glory
and the good intentions.
I'll take the reward.
The role of Han Solo
needed someone older...
with a more cynical edge.
What's that little droid carrying
that's so blasted important?
What's the little droid carrying
that's so important?
Harrison Ford had worked
with Lucas on American Graffiti.
But because the director
initially only wanted new faces...
he was not allowed to audition.
Do I have to sit up
to get in on the right?
Instead, he was brought in
to feed lines to the other actors.
I was given sides and asked if
I would help read the other actors.
It became my task to explain to the
other actors who were coming along...
just what it was that these sides...
were meant to be about.
They're gonna follow us.
They'll destroy your hidden bases.
- They'll destroy the whole system.
- I know.
They'll bring the Death Star too.
Lucas may have been reluctant
to use Ford at first...
but the actor won him over by
giving Han a mix of mercenary swagger...
and world-weariness.
Well, what was so clear was what the
idea was of the character relationships.
Mark was the callow youth,
I was the smart-ass...
and we each had
a clear section of turfto explore.
The planet's totally blown away.
It would've taken 1 ,000 ships with more
firepower than I've ever seen to do it.
If the Empire had a new weapon
that could do this, I'd know about it.
I'd have heard something.
Well, you know about it now.
The enemy's on the move.
We haven't much time.
- I brought you here. Now what?
- We've got to find the rebels.
- What we're carrying belongs to them.
- Their bases are very well hidden, son.
All the power of the Empire
can't find 'em.
Do you know where they are?
No. Not anymore.
I'm not gonna take you on
an impossible chase across the galaxy.
Virtually every young actress
in Hollywood...
tried out for the part
of Princess Leia.
Although the character
was the same age as Luke...
as a leader of the rebellion
Leia needed to project...
a confidence beyond her years.
The plans and specifications
to a battle station...
with enough firepower
to destroy an entire system.
Our only hope in destroying it
is to find its weakness...
which we will determine
from the data I stored in R2.
Now, our only hope
in destroying it...
is to find its weakness...
which we'll do from the data
I stored in R2.
Okay? Now, we've captured the plans
in a raid on the imperial shipyards.
But we fell under attack before
I could get the data to safety...
so I hid it in R2
and sent him off.
When R2 has been safely delivered
to my forces, you get your reward.
You have my guarantee.
What's the little droid carrying
that's so blasted important?
The plans and specifications...
to a battle station
with enough firepower...
to destroy an entire system.
One actress in particular...
seemed tailor-made
to play a princess.
As the daughter of actress Debbie
Reynolds and singer Eddie Fisher...
Carrie Fisher was the product
of Hollywood royalty.
She had no trouble conveying the
self-assurance needed for Leia Organa.
I met with Brian De Palma
and George...
and Brian did all the talking...
because George didn't talk then.
There were incredible actresses my age
being considered for this role...
so I didn't think I would get it.
But our only hope is to destroy it
before it destroys us.
Hiding is useless now.
With the Death Star, they'll continue
to go on destroying systems...
until they've found us.
We have no alternative
but to process the information...
and use it while there's still time.
I got it with the proviso
that I went to a fat farm...
and that I lose 1 0 pounds.
I think they were hoping it was gonna
come out five here and five here.
My character was someone
who was feisty and all of that...
but I felt myself
to be a bit of that too...
so it would have been unlikely that
I would be cast as a shrinking violet.
He cast us to type, in a way.
Lucas's decision to hire unknowns...
went against the advice ofhis friend
Francis Ford Coppola...
who had cast The Godfather
with stage and screen stars.
20th Century Fox
was also concerned...
about Lucas's choice of actors.
They came and said, ''These are the three
unknown people I want to go with. ''
I figured we'd gone down this far
in the road, he knows what he's doing.
I'd be lying if I said
''Oh, my God, Harrison's perfect...
Carrie is perfect,
and Mark is fantastic. ''
No, I was very nervous
about the cast.
For the important role of
aged Jedi master Obi-Wan Kenobi...
Lucas recognized that
he needed an established star.
Sir Alec Guinness was
a veteran of over 40 films...
and had won an Oscar in 1 958...
for his performance in
The Bridge on the River Kwai.
The knighted actor had
the pedigree and the persona.
The Alec Guinness role...
required a certain stability
and gravitas as a character...
which meant we needed a very strong
character actor to play that part.
Signing Guinness was a major coup.
But more casting
would be done in London...
where Star Wars
would be principally produced.
Unlike Lucas's home base
of Northern California...
London provided access to the kind of
massive soundstages...
needed for Star Wars's
ambitious sets.
The location also gave Lucas access
to Britain's top production talents.
The character of Darth Vader demanded
someone of commanding physical stature.
To fill Vader's boots...
Lucas cast champion bodybuilder
David Prowse...
whose resume included roles
like Frankenstein's creature...
in Hammer's
popular horror movies.
As Vader's evil accomplice
Governor Tarkin...
another Hammer alumnus was cast--
63-year-old Peter Cushing.
Best known as the methodical
Professor Van Helsing in Dracula...
Cushing was the perfect choice...
to portray the Death Star's
icy chief administrator.
For the part of Chewbacca, Han Solo's
towering Wookiee copilot...
Lucas and Kurtz had to look
outside normal casting channels.
But at seven feet, three inches tall...
it was no stretch for Peter Mayhew...
who had been working as an orderly
at a Yorkshire hospital.
I sat down
on one of the sofas...
waiting for George.
Door opened...
and George walked in
with Gary behind him.
So naturally, what did I do?
I'm raised in England.
Soon as someone comes in
through the door, I stand up.
George goes--
Virtually turned to Gary and said...
''I think we've found him.''
Finding the right performers to portray
robots was even more of a challenge.
Production designers had constructed
an assortment of robots and androids...
to populate the Star Wars universe.
But it would take living,
breathing actors...
to give personality
to the two main droids...
C-3PO...
and R2-D2.
To operate R2...
Lucas needed a performer small in
stature, but with a big imagination.
Enter 3-foot-5-inch
stage comedian Kenny Baker.
They couldn't find anyone
that would fit inside this robot...
to make it move.
They couldn't use kids
'cause it was quite a heavy machine.
It weighed about 80 pounds.
I'd had a lot of experience
inside costumes...
and inside cats and dogs
and goodness knows what else.
So when I got into the robot,
he said, ''Look happy. ''
So I'd go--
Inside, nobody could
see my expressions, obviously.
But you have to do something
to get the feel of the thing.
Actor Anthony Daniels...
not only had the slender build
needed for C-3PO...
but training as a mime artist.
He'd been seeing people
every five minutes.
I was there for a while and thinking,
''Well, nearly time to go, I guess.''
And then, kind of over
George's shoulder, I saw a painting...
and the most extraordinary
thing happened.
Itjust struck me, because I kind of
looked at this face...
and the face looked back at me, and we
had this extraordinary eye contact.
He's looking out of the picture
and seemed to be saying...
''Come. Come. Be with me.''
The vulnerability in his face...
made me want to help him.
Isn't that weird?
He just looks utterly vulnerable.
That painting completely changed
my attitude to the whole project.
Years later I was able to go
to Ralph McQuarrie and say...
''You realize this is all your fault.''
In March 1 976,
with casting completed...
George Lucas and company
arrived in North Africa.
It was a strange caravan of British
and American filmmakers...
working in a French-speaking nation
on a script few people believed in.
The overriding thing for me
at that stage was...
the amount of work that we had to do,
of stuff there was to achieve...
and we had grave doubts
about getting it done in time.
But the trial by fire
had yet to begin.
It was now up to Lucas
to make his movie.
Just one day into filming...
the Sahara was pelted with its
first major rainfall in 50 years.
We were going out there
to shoot on the salt flat.
I came out in the morning and the rain
was going horizontally down the street.
I thought, ''My God--''
I called a rest day on the crew,
told them to go back to bed...
because there was no way
we were gonna shoot on that.
The first two weeks of shooting,
we'd run into a lot of weather problems.
The sets had blown down,
I didn't get everything shot.
It was a disaster. At that point
I was pretty depressed, saying...
''I've got myself in way over my head.
I don't know what I'm gonna do.''
You must do what you feel
is right, of course.
With temperatures topping
1 00 degrees by midmorning...
Tunisia was anything
but fun in the sun.
Baking for hours
in heavy costume...
even the film's stunt coordinator,
Peter Diamond...
found the conditions
physically exhausting.
I was the only stuntperson
on the picture in Tunisia.
I became a Tusken Raider,
or a Sandperson.
I'm not a sun merchant.
I don't like the sun. I just burn.
So I just died
with the heat of it.
I couldn't stand it anymore,
it was so hot.
There were so many problems.
Itjust was not a good location.
We seem to be made to suffer.
It's our lot in life.
C-3PO was finally...
put together
for the very first time...
the day before
we started shooting.
R2-D2 didn't really
function that well.
He could run along
in the three-legged position...
but he couldn't turn his head
at the same time.
There were wires everywhere.
The head was on a track
ofball bearings.
I used to grab whatever I could and turn
it physically that way and that way.
Not very far.
If I went too far the wires
would go around my neck.
Then they'd say, ''Cut.!
Right, break for lunch. ''
And everybody'djust
walk away and leave me.
Then they'd remember me eventually.
That happened many times.
It was bad enough putting
on the costume for the first time...
and within two paces the left leg
had shattered down...
onto the plastic of the left foot...
and was gently
but forcibly and persistently...
knifing it...
into the soft part of my foot.
So we took it off,and I limped
to the set with one foot.
It was then I began to panic
about the days to come.
As the actors and crew began to grumble
about the adverse conditions...
it was Sir Alec Guinness who served
as a role model of professionalism.
It was, for me, fascinating
to watch Alec Guinness.
He was always prepared,
always professional...
always very kind to the other actors.
He had a very clear head
about how to serve the story.
He was the person who sort of
brought it some legitimacy.
I asked him
why he wanted to do it.
He loved the idea
of playing a mentor or a wizard...
in a morality play...
where good and evil
are so clearly defined.
Action!
- How long have you had these droids?
- Three or four seasons.
They're up for sale if you want them.
Let me see your identification.
You don't need to see
his identification.
I don't need to see
your identification.
These aren't the droids
you're looking for.
we're looking for.
He can go about his business.
You can go about your business.
Move along.
Lucas, meanwhile...
was up to his neck
in malfunctioning props...
electronic breakdowns...
and other production woes.
Star Wars was already
struggling to stay on schedule.
The only silver lining
was that after Tunisia...
the production would be moving to
a more controlled environment--
Elstree Studios outside London.
The stages at Elstree were among
the largest in the world...
and the sets, now finished
after months of construction...
werejust as impressive.
For the first time,
the entire Star Wars cast was together.
That was almost like
a whole separate movie.
It was like getting
a whole, fresh start.
And it was all new, really.
We were all
very different ages.
I was 1 9, Harrison was 33.
He was sort of
the big man on campus.
Meeting him,you sort of felt,
''Well, he'll be a movie star. ''
Costumes, makeup,
robots and aliens...
were all ready to go.
I put that mask on
and Chewie transformed me.
I transformed.
The attitude was different.
The walk was different.
Chewie turned on.
Do the scenes, come back,
take the mask off...
Peter was back.
Action.
That old man's mad.
You said it, Chewie.
Boy, where did you
dig up that old fossil?
- Ben is a great man.
- Great at getting us into trouble.
I didn't hear you give any ideas.
Cut.
But working
at Elstree Studios...
didn't mean the production
was free from problems...
or strict British union regulations.
At 5:30 we had to stop...
unless we were
in the middle of a shot.
I could ask the crew
for an extra 1 5 minutes...
but they always voted me down.
Not to put down the British crew, but
there was an attitude of''What's this?''
It didn't help that most
of the crew thought Star Wars...
was just a children's film.
At times even the actors were
hard-pressed to take the work seriously.
Didn't think it was gonna be any good.
At least I didn't.
I thought, ''This is a bit strange.''
I can remember
this lighting man--
He said, ''What is all this about?
It's a load of rubbish. ''
And we all thought the same at
the time-- ''Yeah, it's a bit strange.''
Action!
It was a princess with her hair
in weird buns on the side...
and a giant in a monkey suit
or something.
I mean,
it was very, very weird.
No more adventures!
I'm not getting involved!
Don't you call me a mindless philosopher
you overweight glob of grease!
Bang!
I'm going to regret this.
It was tough dialogue to say.
So I got, ''Governor Tarkin, I thought
I recognized your foul stench. ''
Which, I don't know about you,
but I'm always talking like that.
Governor Tarkin.
I should have expected to find you
holding Vader's leash.
I recognized your foul stench
when I was brought on board.
Charming to the last.
We used to say, ''You can type
this stuff, but you can't say it.''
George didn't really like
being in London...
I suppose,
is the best way to say it.
He doesn't like
being away from home.
He's not the most
gregarious person in the world.
He had some clashes
with the cameraman.
Gil Taylor was a very old-school
cameraman-- very crotchety.
George, coming out of
low-budget filmmaking...
was used to doing
a lot of things himself.
So George would say things like,
''Well, put a light here. ''
And Gil took offense
at that kind of thing.
He says, ''That's not yourjob, son. ''
''You tell me what
you want to see, and I'll do it...
the way I think is best
to create what you want to see.''
It was a clash
of style of working.
Slate 3 27, take four.
We're coming up
on Alderaan.
I did feel something.
I could almost see the remote.
That's good.
You've taken your first step
into a larger world.
Lucas also became frustrated...
that the costumes, sets
and other production elements...
weren't living up
to his vision for Star Wars.
The compromises required
due to the film's budget...
plagued him
on an almost daily basis.
What was disappointing
would be the cantina sequence.
It was really
imaginatively described...
and then you go in there...
and it looks like
The Nutcracker Suite.
There's a frog guy
and a mouse girl...
and a giant cricket at the bar.
It was just really disappointing.
But George says, ''Don't worry.
We're gonna fix all of this. ''
We didn't see anything
of what ended up on the screen.
So when they blew my planet up...
I was looking at a guy going like this
against a board with a circle on it.
I mean, it was funny.
Proceed with the operation.
You may fire when ready.
What?
Dantooine is too remote
to make an effective demonstration.
We will deal with your rebel friends
soon enough.
Bang!
And you call yourselves humans.
George never talked.
We felt he wanted us
to hit our marks...
and magically
accommodate our dialogue.
He lost his voice at one point.
We didn't know that for days.
And we wanted to get him
a little board that said...
''Faster and more intense.''
That was his main direction.
Hejust wanted us
to speed through it.
George is notorious
for saying, after a take...
''Do it again.
Faster, more intensity. ''
He certainly said to me, ''Terrific,
Tony. Can you do it again, faster?''
But I didn't get
''more intensity.''
I didn't think 3PO with more intensity
would be bearable. Do you?
I said all systems have been alerted
to your presence, sir.
The main entrance seems
to be the only way in or out.
We all had to fill in
a lot of the blanks.
It was more a matter of, if we did
something he didn't like he'd tell us...
rather than telling us what to do.
I think George likes people.
I think George
is a warmhearted person.
But, yeah, he's a little impatient
with the process of acting...
of finding something,
you know.
He thinks it's there.
''It's right there.
I wrote it down.'' You know?
''Do that.'' You know? And sometimes you
can't just ''do that'' and make it work.
He's really focused on what he's
trying to do and get everything right.
Is the smoke right?
Did the squibs go off right?
And we were just
taunting him mercilessly.
Carrie and Mark have
wicked sense ofhumors.
Carrie was very young...
and Mark was very young...
so they were
the junior division...
and they were always
lurking about on set.
So it kept us in stitches.
I got one outfit
for the first movie...
and as George taught me...
there is no underwear in space.
Instead of that,
there is gaffer tape.
So I was taped down.
And I used to say, we should just
make up a contest on the call sheet...
as to who's gonna rip it off.
But we didn't do that.
We were all goofing around
and trying to make George crack...
'cause he looked like
he was ready to burst into tears.
You'd try and cheer him up.
Go.
- Okay, cut.
- Cut it.
- And?
Carrie and Mark bumped in too early.
The mike was in frame.
The mike was in picture.
Go back to first positions.
The sound department
has to pay up.
That, to him, was really
inappropriate humor at the time...
because I'm sure he's in the zone
and seeing what he wants to do...
and we're just actors
trying to stave off boredom...
because we've been in
the trash compactor all morning.
Ready? And action!
- What happened?
- I don't know!
It just disappeared!
I got a really bad feeling
about this.
But it is amazing what you can do
when you have a vision, an ambition...
and when you can bend
other people's will to your desire.
The thing that kept it focused
towards the ambitions...
was George's vision
and his passion for the idea.
Perhaps the most memorable
stunt in Star Wars...
was actually performed
by Mark Hamill and Carrie Fisher--
the nick-of-time escape
of Luke and Leia...
across a yawning chasm
in the Death Star.
Mark Hamill wanted to do
as much as he could himself.
I had times when I had to keep him back
because he was too enthusiastic.
He could've got hurt.
Princess Leia and Luke Skywalker
had to swing over this void.
We couldn't afford doubles, so I said,
''I can teach them. It'll be safe. ''
My buddy and I, we put the harnesses on,
we put the wires on.
Everyone down below.
Remember, we are about 20 meters up...
looking down on them.
And as we swung across
there was a terrible tear.
My buddy said to me,
''Peter, your harness has snapped.''
Mark said, ''I'm not going in that.
It's too dangerous. ''
This is where I discovered
you had to be a good liar.
I said, ''There's nothing wrong with the
harness. I split my pants as I landed. ''
He said, ''Oh, I thought
that was the harness.''
I said, ''I wouldn't let you
do this if it was dangerous.''
Action!
They did it in one take,
and that's how we got it.
For luck.
That was really early on
in the shoot...
when I was still
worried about my weight.
I thought we were gonna miss
and I'd hit the wall...
and they will say, ''Still too tubby.
Let's bring in Jodie Foster.''
Another of
Peter Diamond's tasks...
was choreographing
the dramatic lightsaber battle...
between Darth Vader
and Obi-Wan Kenobi.
You can't win, Darth.
If my blade should find its mark,
you will cease to exist.
But I warn you,
if you strike me down...
I shall become more powerful
than you can possibly imagine.
George wanted a broadsword
type of fight...
with a touch ofJapanese behind it.
But instead of becoming
samurai moves with one hand...
I kept it with two hands...
so all the moves were two hands,
completely like that.
The first swords
were bits of wood...
with front-projection material
wrapped around them.
Now, the hardest thing for me
on the first fights--
Darth Vader was a very heavy man...
Obi-Wan Kenobi was
a gentleman, right...
who had done some fencing
in the theater.
I had to teach them,
if that was a sword...
to stop before they touched,
'cause the blades were breaking.
We broke so many blades.
They just kept snapping.
- Cut.
- Cut it!
Across the Atlantic, Fox's head
of production, Alan Ladd,Jr....
continued to offer Lucas his main...
if not his only,
support from the studio.
There was a lot of problems,yes.
Every board meeting I attended,
the subject was always Star Wars.
''The costs are rising.
It's this, it's that.
Look, we've read drafts of scripts...
that make no sense to us
in any way, shape or form. ''
It was rather unpleasant.
The things that stick in my mind
that made me laugh were, like...
memos worried about whether or not
the Wookiee should have pants.
They're looking at this thing
and saying...
''Couldn't he have some lederhosen?''
And I thought,
''Isn't this great?
You know, of all the things
to worry about.
The Wookiee has no pants.''
I think we were
two weeks over schedule.
At that point, the board of directors
at Fox started to panic...
and tell Alan Ladd,Jr. that he had to
shut that film down regardless.
So he came to me and said...
''Look, you've gotta finish
in the next week...
because I've got another board meeting,
and I can't say we're still shooting.''
I kept phoning their production
department saying, ''This is insane.
If we put on a second crew, it costs us
more than going an extra week.''
They said, ''It doesn't matter.
The studio's opinion...
is that the day deadline is more
important than the money you spend.''
The final scenes were filmed
at breakneck speed...
with Lucas
frantically bicycling...
from one soundstage to another.
I think George suffered a lot more
than I was aware of at the time.
But I was very focused
on what I was doing...
'cause this was a very busy movie,
just nonstop dawn to dusk.
We did go over at the end...
and we split into three units
right at the end.
Gary directed the second unit...
and I had the distinction of directing
the third unit of Star Wars.
My shots were things like close-up
of R2-D2's third foot going down.
Nothing too dramatic.
But that's how we finished it.
Come on.
Okay, cut. Time up. Cut.
I hope that old man got the tractor beam
down, or this is gonna be a short trip.
Hit it!
Fox originally slated Star Wars
for a Christmas release in 1 976.
Schmuck.
463, take one.
But the diffiicult shoot had put
the film severely behind schedule.
Action.
- Didn't we just leave this party?
- Give us a growl.
- What kept you?
- We ran into some old friends.
- Is the ship all right?
- Seems okay, if we can get to it.
I just hope the old man got
the tractor beam out of commission.
- Look.
- Now's our chance. Go!
With barely six months to go...
there was almost no chance
of delivering the project on time.
Okay, cut.
I hadjust finished shooting the movie,
and I was exhausted, basically...
but I had to go right from the shooting
into the finishing without a break.
Already anxious
about meeting his deadline...
Lucas was shocked when he saw the first
assembly ofhis edited film that spring.
Sir, the groiters are losing power!
All right. I'll get it.
The first cut of Star Wars
was an unmitigated disaster.
- How's that?
- Yes, that's much better.
I'd started to see things cut together.
I wasn't happy with it.
I'd come in on weekends,
and I'd recut the film on my own.
Cut.
And I tried to get the editor
to cut it my way...
and he didn't really want to,
and so I had to let the editor go.
So I had no editor.
I was behind schedule.
I had to race to finish the movie.
1 77, take two.
Lucas realized his only hope
was to start from scratch.
And I am C-3PO,
human-cyborg relations.
And this is
my counterpart, R2-D2.
- Oh, hello.
- Okay, cut.
To recut the movie, he hired
Paul Hirsch and Richard Chew...
and for several months he was able
to borrow his wife, Marcia...
who was editing New York, New York
with Martin Scorsese.
Slate 250, take seven.
Action.
You must do what you feel
is right, of course.
Right now
I don't feel too good.
On Star Wars,
the trio's first task...
was to give the film an energy
and pace that was sorely lacking.
Cut.
It was cut in a very traditional manner
ofjust playing things out in masters...
and then going
into the coverage...
and let the actors'rhythms
dictate the cuts...
rather than having the cuts...
kind of drive the rhythm of the scenes.
21 1 , take three.
Guide track.
Action!
So consequently,
there wasn't any excitement...
in the footage the way
that it had been put together.
Cut.
Richard and I would leapfrog.
If he was on reel one,
I would grab reel two.
Whoever finished that would
grab reel three and so forth.
We used shots up until
the very last frame.
- Cut.
- Can I take another one?
Very often, the very next frame would be
the flash of the camera stop.
For instance, there's a shot
of one of the Sandpeople...
who knocks Luke down, and then
he holds his weapon up over his head.
He did it once. We rocked it back and
forth so he did it a number of times.
The only things that are there
is what's presentable...
and everything
behind the scenes is a mess.
With no chance
ofbeing ready by Christmas...
a new release date
was set for summer, 1 977.
Some doubted that the movie
would ever reach theaters.
But as bad as things
had been with the editing...
the situation at ILM
was even worse.
The company was trying to create effects
that had never been done before.
They knew what they
wanted to accomplish...
but they had yet to create
anything usable for the film.
They had spent half their budget...
and ultimately I had about four shots,
none of which I would accept.
They were just not good.
That was a low point.
I had no special effects. I didn't know
if we were gonna get the ships to work.
So it was a pretty desperate time.
And we'd spent half the budget
building the motion-control cameras...
and setting the shop up.
It was a disaster to say the least.
The factory has to be built...
before the first can of peas
can be sent to the supermarket.
And I think it was a year or more...
without any film coming out,
without one shot being finished.
'Cause they were building
optical printers and cameras.
We were building models.
I know that George was
disappointed in the work...
and I'm disappointed
that he was disappointed.
But there's a certain subjectivity
to some of that stuff.
I wish he'd been happier,
but I also think that ultimately...
the work did thejob.
When word of the postproduction problems
reached the Fox board of directors...
they decided they'd had enough of
George Lucas and ''that science movie. ''
I just sat in one
executive committee meeting...
where they're hauling me
over the coals.
I just said,
''It's the greatest picture ever made.''
That ended the conversation.
They were afraid to say,
''Well,you're stupid and you're wrong...
and we want you out of this building
by 5:00 this afternoon. ''
There were some tense moments there.
With the dismal
early cut of the film...
ILM in chaos and growing pressure
from the studio...
Lucas was facing almost
unbearable battles on a daily basis.
After an especially
tense trip to ILM...
Lucas felt sharp chest pains.
Fearing a heart attack, the director
checked into a Marin County hospital.
He was diagnosed with
hypertension and exhaustion...
and was warned
to reduce his stress level.
At that point, I really felt...
I'd gotten myself into a real mess and
didn't know whether I was gonna get out.
Lucas doubled his efforts
to save Star Wars.
The situation at ILM
required drastic measures.
To get the film's crucial
special effects back on track...
Lucas had no choice
but to step in personally.
We put a production department in
at the special effects company.
I went there twice a week.
There was a certain amount
of resentment at first...
because they felt...
that they were being challenged a bit
on how they had set it up.
We felt that there was a certain
quasi-hippie mentality...
that some of them had
about the schedule.
Ultimately, I guess
we were known as a country club.
I think it looked to those guys
that there needed to be...
a really strong
production force in there...
that was going to meet
some sort of quota.
With hundreds of shots
left to be completed...
ILM would have to do a year's worth
of work in just six months.
But Lucas and Kurtz were determined
to turn the situation around.
Gary was a gearhead,
so he could understand our problems.
And George is a storyteller...
and so we have to serve his needs...
because he's the one
that's telling the story.
But we had to build these incredible
contraptions in order to do it.
George was our general.
We're his soldiers.
And we're all
fighting this single battle...
to get this film out.
We were on the front lines...
and that gave us also
kind of a feeling of being special...
and fighting this great battle
to get this thing done, whatever it is.
Luke, pull up.!
To help inspire
the effects team at ILM...
Lucas had spliced together aerial
dogfights from old war movies.
That would be like the first animatic,
which you do in the computer now...
and we matched frame to frame and
the action on that as close as we could.
It was hugely helpful.
- I got him.!
- Great, kid! Don't get cocky.
To describe that abstract world
of a battle is impossible.
Storyboards don't do it, as far as the
pacing, the rhythms that he needed.
- Thanks, Wedge.
- That was great.
As fall turned to winter, Star Wars
finally started to take shape.
That's it! We did it!
We did it!
Working from
the raw production tracks...
sound designer Ben Burtt would add
a critical new layer to the film.
Burtt had spent a year
building a catalog of sounds...
for things that didn't exist
in our galaxy.
George introduced the idea of what
he called an ''organic sound track. ''
George thought that Chewbacca
might be made up...
from recordings of dogs
or maybe even bears.
In addition, I recorded some lions
and tigers and even some walruses.
I would begin
editing them together...
and making little phrases
out of the noises.
I would take the recordings
and edit the best pieces.
You know, the bear might make
a sound that sounded angry.
Or they might make a sound
that was cute.
Or a sound like a sentence--
a ''wah, wah'' kind of a sound.
You said it, Chewie.
The voice of R2 turned out to be
the most difficult problem to solve...
in the sound design
of the first movie...
because R2 had to act
alongside of the other actors.
And the script only said...
that R2 made a sound,
or maybe R2 beeped.
I had a small
electronic synthesizer...
and I did some patches with it
and made up some electronic sounds.
But that didn't sound alive.
At one point we talked
about R2's personality...
and we felt he was developing
kind of as a toddler.
So I did a lot
ofbaby recordings...
and eventually we found that
in the discussion of R2's voice...
we were making
the sounds ourselves.
A few experiments led to
the combination of using my voice...
doing baby talk--
beeps and boops--
with the electronic synthesizer.
So R2 is sort of 50% machine
and 50% organic...
coming out of
the performance of a person.
The breathing for Vader was recorded
by putting a little tiny microphone...
down inside
a regulator on a scuba tank.
I breathed through the mask itself,
and it breathed in and out...
and out of that came the various
paces of Vader breathing.
And that sound worked out
pretty successfully.
Finding the right voice for Darth Vader
was another challenge.
And action!
Lucas never intended to use the on-set
vocal performance of David Prowse.
Start tearing this ship apart, piece
by piece, until you find those tapes!
Find the passengers in this vessel!
I want them alive!
I can still hear
David Prowse's accent...
in the Darth Vader mask, muffled,
'cause he would do the real dialogue...
in trying to curse
Carrie Fisher or something.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I'm a member of the Imperial Senate
on a diplomatic mission--
You are part of the Rebel Alliance
and a traitor. Take her away!
It was hilarious and terrifying
at the same time...
'cause we didn't know
what Darth sounded like.
That was the first time we heard him.
We were like, ''Is that it?
Is he gonna be some Scottish guy,
or what is this?''
Prowse's voice would later be replaced
with a more menacing performance...
provided by classically trained
stage and film actorJames Earl Jones.
George had hired David Prowse...
but he said he wanted
a so-called ''darker'' voice.
Not in terms of ethnic,
but in terms of timbre.
The rumor is that he thought
of Orson Welles...
and then probably thought that Orson
might be too recognizable.
So what he ends up is picking
a voice that was born in Mississippi...
raised in Michigan, and was a stutterer.
And that happened
to be my voice.
I want to know what happened
to the plans they sent you.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I'm a member of the Imperial Senate
on a diplomatic mission to Alderaan.
You are part of
the Rebel Alliance and a traitor.
Take her away!
C-3PO's voice struck us all as
''We've got to do something about that.''
Thirty-four, take three.
We seem to be made to suffer.
It's our lot in life.
It was mentioned
a number of times...
that C-3PO might sound
like a used car salesman.
Not the English butler type.
Oh, I'm sorry, sir.
I must have fallen over.
I just came up with this voice
of an over-the-top British butler.
British because that would
be my natural mode of thinking.
A butler because
that was his role in life.
Nervous because that
was his feeling in life.
And it came as, ''C-3PO,
human-cyborg relations.''
This is my counterpart,
R2-D2.
Hello.
A few people
were brought in to record...
and an attempt was made
to see how 3PO would be...
with different kinds of voices.
I believe 30 actors coming,
and some really quite impressive names.
Stan Freberg and a few others
were auditioned.
Apparently one of them
was a major cartoon actor...
a man of literally a thousand voices,
who eventually said...
''You know something, George, Tony's
voice is pretty good for the character.
Why don't you
just use his voice?''
And eventually the discussion
just quieted down...
and it was an
excellent performance.
It synchronized
with his body motions.
It was a total character
which he created.
His track was left in the movie.
- Hey. We don't serve their kind here.
- What?
Your droids-- they'll have to wait
outside. We don't want them here.
Wait out by the speeder.
We don't want any trouble.
I heartily agree with you, sir.
Cut.
428, take seven.
Action.
Here we go.
Cut in the sublight engines.
At long last,
the editing, sound...
and visual effects
were taking shape.
But a private screening of the film
for Lucas's closest friends...
didn't do much
to bolster his confidence.
It was an early stage, you know,
sort of a second or third cut.
I had a couple of my friends
come up to see it.
Brian De Palma was in town.
Steven came.
Some other friends
came to see it.
The human characters
and the sets were there...
but, of course, all the spectacular--
you know, the Death Star fight...
and the battle inside the trench...
and all that was just...
not even there to be seen.
So, the reaction was not
a good one. I loved the movie.
I was one of the only people
in the audience that liked the movie.
All my friends were very honest:
''I don't get it. What are you doing?''
That was basically
the tenor of the whole thing.
On the other hand,
the studio and Laddie...
and his little group
saw the film.
They loved it. It was the first time
I've actually shown a film...
and one of the executives
even cried at the screening.
It was very emotional for him.
I sat my family round
the kitchen table in my house...
and I said, ''The most extraordinary
day of my life...
has just taken place,
and I want you to remember this day.
Because this is what I never dreamed--
or maybe I dreamed--
but I never thought I would have
a day's experience...
like the day I've had today
in seeing this film.''
I couldn't even believe it.
At that point I was used to studio
chiefs saying, ''This is terrible.
You shouldn't show this to
an audience. Embarrassing.''
So, it was very rewarding to show it to
people, even though it was in bad shape.
It didn't help that one critical
element in Star Wars was still missing--
There's no lock.
the musical score.
- That oughta hold them for a while.
- Quick. We've got to get across.
-Find the controls to extend the bridge.
-I think I just blasted it.
They're coming through!
I remember bugging George.
''When can we hear the score?''
Fortunately, Lucas was able
to recruit...
one of the industry's most accomplished
composers,John Williams.
Williams had recently won an Oscar
for Steven Spielberg's Jaws...
and his resume included countless film
and television scores...
including music for the original
Lost in Space television series.
I do remember George
talking about the fact...
that what we were going to see
in the film...
represents worlds
that we hadn't seen...
but that the music should give us
some kind of an emotional anchor.
We heard a romantic melody
for Princess Leia.
We heard bellicose music
for the battle scenes.
And some very heavy
declamatory thing for Darth Vader.
In March, 1 977...
John Williams led
the London Symphony Orchestra...
in the performance
of the Star Wars soundtrack.
Recorded over 1 2 days, it was
a sweeping symphonic masterpiece...
one of the few things to actually
exceed Lucas's expectations.